Ahsan Naveed Malik Resume

AHSAN NAVEED MALIK



ahsann.malik7@outlook.com (+92)03348767980





Rawalpindi, Pakistan

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahsanmalik7/

An accomplished, ambitious and committed IT professional with proven record of working in diverse and challenging work environments. Having a broad experience of leading and managing a team to being a team player in top tech industries.



SKILLS -

Programing Languages: Python, C++/C#, Java, JavaScript, HTML, PHP, MySQL,

Frameworks/Libraries: Pandas, Pyro, numpy, scipy, Sockets, STL, Beautifulsoup, Basic Sellenium

Tools: PyCharm, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, Azur Devops, Docker, **Kubernetes**

Computer Skills: MS Windows, Linux Client and Server Hardware: Sensors, Raspberry Pi, Arduino Board

Organization Skills: Scrum, Agile, Teamwork, Pressure handling

Effective decision making

Soft Skills: Ability to work individually and as a team member, good communication skills, good ability to adapt to multicultural environments, open minded, ability to look for creative solutions

CERTIFICATIONS

- SAFe Practitioner
- Certified Scrum Master
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) -CSCO11908367,
- Cisco Certified Network Professional(CCNP) Route and Switch

Projects Completed

(vsftp) Servers Deployment

Autonomous Edge Resource Self-organizing Algorithm, Python based Network Emulator Implementation of Navigation System in C++ Web Scrapping in python, Peer 2 Peer based Intrusion Detection System, Video Player on Raspberry PI, Web Kiosk on Raspberry PI, Proxy Server Deployment, FTP

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Analyst II at S&P Global, Islamabad, Pakistan November 2019 - Present

- Elicited Business requirements from stakeholders across departments, Clarifying functional and technical requirements between the stakeholders by applying different visual modelling techniques as workflow diagrams, process flow.
- Analysing Business processes and revamping them for the digital strategy.
- Delivered projects covering all aspects of project management methodology, following KPIs guide, including scoping requirement, implementation checklists, resource requirements/scheduling,
- Removing impediments and making development team self-organizing to deliver products.
- Enabling Agile environment by acting as a SCRUM Master for executing projects in SCRUM framework

S&P Global Market Intelligence

ACHEIVEMENTS

- Worked with DevOps team for development of Microservices and creation of reusable Docker templates.
- Provided analytical insights to different blockers and impediments blocking the team to proceed further with the goals
- Successfully carried out product release activities

Research/Software Engineer at Huawei Technologies, Munich, Germany **February 2016 – August 2019**

- Researched in the area of adaptive, resilient control planes for programmable networks
- Provided Analytical insights to State of the art of algorithms and the performance issues
- Designed reliable and low latency Software Defined Network control plane algorithm for 5G
- Extended Emulation tool to test for different new protocols with real work network
- Integrated Docker nodes into emulation tool, with fully automated resource creation and deployment
- Maintained of Linux Servers for lab support work for the team platform and worked on Demo development



Published Papers

- Autonomous Edge Resource Organization with Smallcell Integration in 5G, "ICCW 2018"
- Towards Coreless Wireless Mobile Networks, "Globecom Workshop 2018

Software/Hardware Engineer at Passivhaus Institute, Darmstadt, Germany **August 2015 – January 2016**

- Development and improvement of measurement and data acquisition systems (hardware and software)
- Development and improvement of software and computing tools in the field of building physics, building simulation, energy efficiency, building technology and building energy-
- Development and implementation of algorithms and interfaces
- Programming and maintenance of web applications, servers and integration of databases

Passivhaus Institut

ACHEIVEMENTS

- Successful Integration of smart plugs and sensors with Raspbery pi
- Installation of self-developed monitoring Equipment in to different location with remote web access to collected data



ACHEIVEMENTS

- Achieved Shining star of the month award
- Successfully handled and manged the network maintenance activity

Operations Engineer at Nayatel Pvt Ltd, Islamabad, Pakistan August 2010 – August 2011

- Network designing, installation, configuration & troubleshooting
- Implementation and troubleshooting of PPPoE, IP Routed & P2P circuits
- Configuration & Troubleshooting of MPLS based L2/L3 VPNs, OSPF, ISIS and BGP, BRASES for xDSL customers
- Optimization of converged IP/MPLS network
- Configuration of ALCATEL ONTs and OLTs for internet, BPON, GPON
- Network Level Support to TAC, Field Engineers, Telecom Operators/Corporate customers
 - Coordination with upstream/backbone internet providers

INTERIM WORK EXPERIENCE

Student Job at HRZ, TU Darmstadt, Germany December 2011 – July 2015



- Configuration and maintenance of CISCO Router and Switches
- Configuring OSPF EIGRP, RIP and STP
- Implementation and troubleshooting of IPSec VPN,
 MPLS VPN and remote DHCP Server
- Configuration and maintenance of ASA firewall

Internship

Huawei European Research Centre, Munich, Germany June 2013 - January 2014



- Embedding Problem formulation for PIP Orchestrator: theoretical problem formulation, narrowing down the range of potential solutions; Defining algorithms for solving PIP Orchestrator Embedding Problem in Java
- In an OpenStack test environment, enable mapping real application graphs to virtual resources requirements;
- Writing OpenStack scripts in Python Published Papers
- VNetMapper: A fast and scalable approach to virtual networks embedding." ICCCN, 2014

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Masters Information and Communication Engineering

Technical University of Darmstadt
October 2011 – January 2015

BE Electrical Engineering (Major in Telecommunication)

Air University, Islamabad, Pakistan September 2006 – July 2010

- Master Thesis: Peer-to-Peer based Intrusion Detection System
- A collaborative architecture for intrusion detection in a distributed system
- Detection of real time network threats using existing IDS mechanism such as SNORT/BRO
- Use of MySql for reading alerts
- Implementation of Peer-to-Peer protocol Kademlia in C++ using multithreading

Implementation of design on Raspberry Pi

- Bachelor Thesis: IP based Wireless Sensor Network
- TCP/IP communication used for point-to-point flows between arbitrary nodes
- Collecting data from various sensors and sending it to a remote server Implementation of design on Atmega168, Enc28j60, Arduino board

Resume Ahsan Naveed Malik

Personal Interests & Hobbies

- Poster Designing
- Creating pieces of arts
- Cooking, Reading Books, movies
- Tennis, Cricket and Football
- Participated in LUMS OLYMPIAD 2008 for Painting Competition, held at LUMS, Lahore, Pakistan
- Participated in **GIKI MEDIA FESTIVAL M FEST 2009** for Poster Design, Swabi, Pakistan
- Participated in ARTS competition held at **NOMAD ART GALLERY**, Islamabad, Pakistan